## **Software Developer**

# **HWEE SHAN WONG**

+44 7424 586 826

HweeWong

#### **EXPERIENCE**

### Natwest Group, Edinburgh

**Software Engineer |** since April 2018

[ { "item": "• Automated the onboarding process to developer tools. Reduced cycle time from 48 hrs to 5 mins." }, { "item": "• Delivered microservices in event-driven architecture and have deep understanding of the architecture." }, { "item": "• Collaborated closely with customers/SMEs in agile development. >50% reduction in cycle time from development to release" }, { "item": "• Cultivated the culture of BDD, TDD within the team which enhanced system reliability and team's devops metrics." }, { "item": "• Presented proof of concepts for different IAM integration of tools." }, { "item": "• Led migration work for on-prem SaaS product." } ]

#### Natwest Group, Edinburgh

**Technology Service Analyst** | Sep 2017 – Apr 2018

[ { "item": "• Migrated server data from bespoke tools to ServiceNow CMDB for better consolidation of data within the enterprise." }, { "item": "• Embedded agile methodology for the project through creation of short-term, manageable goals and Kanban dashboards." }, { "item": "• Improved communications plans with stakeholders to ensure transparency and effective communication." } ]

#### Merck, Sharp & Dohme (MSD), Newcastle

Chemical Engineer | Aug 2015 - Sep 2016

[ { "item": "• Supported technical operations in solid-dose tablet production facility and operated within GMP standards." }, { "item": "• Led incidents/deviations investigations to identify root causes using Lean Six Sigma methodologies." }, { "item": "• Generated technical memorandums for process improvements. Implementation of new design reduced operation downtime." } ]

#### **EDUCATION**

#### First Class Honors

MEng Chemical Engineering with Industrial Experience, University of Manchester | Sep 2013 – Jun 2017

4A\* in Chemistry, Biology, Physics, Mathematics

A Levels, Taylor's College | Jan 2012 – Jun 2013

#### CVILLO

### **About me**

Hi, my name is Hwee and currently a software engineer in Natwest Group. I am passionate about developing tools and products to boost engineering experience for other engineers. I have experience in delivering microservices using the twelve-factor app methodology. I have also worked on implementing infrastructure solutions and services.